[
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": "Which question no longer concerns the modern software engineer",
        "answer": " Why does computer hardware cost so much?",
        "options": [
            " Why does computer hardware cost so much?",
            "Why does software take a long time to finish?",
            "Why does it cost so much to develop a piece of software?",
            "Why canâ€™t software errors be removed from products prior to delivery?"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "Software is a product and can be manufactured using the same technologies used for other engineering artifacts?",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "Software deteriorates rather than wears out because",
        "answer": "Multiple change requests introduce errors in component interactions",
        "options": [
            "Software suffers from exposure to hostile environments",
            "Defects are more likely to arise after software has been used often",
            "Multiple change requests introduce errors in component interactions",
            "Software spare parts become harder to order"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": "WebApps are a mixture of print publishing and software development, making their development outside the realm of software engineering practice.",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "There are no real differences between creating WebApps and MobileApps.",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "In its simplest form an external computing device may access cloud data services using a web browser.",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "Product line software development depends the reuse of existing software components to provide software engineering leverage.",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": "Which of the items listed below is not one of the software engineering layers?",
        "answer": "Manufacturing",
        "options": [
            "Process",
            "Manufacturing",
            "Methods",
            "Tools"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "Software engineering umbrella activities are only applied during the initial phases of software development projects.",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "Which of these are the 5 generic software engineering framework activities?",
        "answer": "communication, planning, modeling, construction, deployment",
        "options": [
            "communication, planning, modeling, construction, deployment",
            "communication, risk management, measurement, production, reviewing",
            "analysis, designing, programming, debugging, maintenance",
            "analysis, planning, designing, programming, testing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": "Planning ahead for software reuse reduces the cost and increases the value of the systems into which they are incorporated.",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": "The essence of software engineering practice might be described as understand the problem, plan a solution, carry out the plan, and examine the result for accuracy.",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "In agile process models the only deliverable work product is the working program.",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "A most software development projects are initiated to try to meet some business need.",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "In general software only succeeds if its behavior is consistent with the objectives of its designers.",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": "Which of the following are recognized process flow types?",
        "answer": "both b and c",
        "options": [
            "Concurrent process flow",
            "Iterative process flow",
            "Linear process flow",
            "both b and c"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": "The communication activity is best handled for small projects using six distinct actions (inception, elicitation, elaboration, negotiation, specification, validation).",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "A good software development team always uses the same task set for every project to insure high quality work products",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": "Software processes can be constructed out of pre-existing software patterns to best meet the needs of a software project.",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "Which of these are standards for assessing software processes?",
        "answer": "both b and d",
        "options": [
            "SEI",
            "SPICE",
            "ISO 9000",
            "ISO 9001",
            "both b and d"
        ]
    },
    
    {
        "numb": 41,
        "question": "The waterfall model of software development is",
        "answer": "A reasonable approach when requirements are well defined.",
        "options": [
            "A reasonable approach when requirements are well defined.",
            "A good approach when a working program is required quickly.",
            "An old fashioned model that is rarely used any more."


 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 42,
        "question": "The incremental model of software development is",
        "answer": "A good approach when a working core product is required quickly.",
        "options": [
            "A reasonable approach when requirements are well defined.",
            "A good approach when a working core product is required quickly.",
            "A revolutionary model that is not used for commercial products."


 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 43,
        "question": "Evolutionary software process models",
        "answer": "All of the above.",
        "options": [
            "Are iterative in nature.",
            "Can easily accommodate product requirements changes.",
            "Do not generally produce throwaway systems.",
            "All of the above."


 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 44,
        "question": "The prototyping model of software development is",
        "answer": "A useful approach when a customer cannot define requirements clearly.",
        "options": [
            "A reasonable approach when requirements are well defined.",
            "A useful approach when a customer cannot define requirements clearly.",
            "A risky model that rarely produces a meaningful product."



 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 45,
        "question": "The spiral model of software development",
        "answer": "Includes project risks evaluation during each iteration.",
        "options": [
            "Ends with the delivery of the software product.",
            "Includes project risks evaluation during each iteration.",
            "All of the above."




 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 46,
        "question": "The concurrent development model is",
        "answer": "Both a and b",
        "options": [
            "Another name for concurrent engineering.",
            "Defines events that trigger engineering activity state transitions.",
            "Both a and b"



 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 47,
        "question": "The component-based development model is",
        "answer": "Dependent on object technologies for support.",
        "options": [
            "Only appropriate for computer hardware design.",
            "Not able to support the development of reusable components.",
            "Dependent on object technologies for support."


 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 48,
        "question": "The formal methods model of software development makes use of mathematical methods to",
        "answer": "All of the above.",
        "options": [
            "Define the specification for computer-based systems.",
            "Develop defect free computer-based systems.",
            "Verify the correctness of computer-based systems.",
            "All of the above."



 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 49,
        "question": "Which of these is not one of the phase names defined by the Unified Process model for software development?",
        "answer": "Validation phase",
        "options": [
            "Inception phase",
            "Construction phase",
            "Validation phase"


 ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 50,
        "question": "Which of these is not a characteristic of Personal Software Process?",
        "answer": "Practitioner requires careful supervision by the project manager.",
        "options": [
            "Emphasizes personal measurement of work product.",
            "Practitioner requires careful supervision by the project manager.",
            "Practitioner is empowered to control quality of software work products."















































        ]
    }
]